hey everyone welcome back to this tosa
automation playlist today we are going
to talk about how you can scroll down a
page uh which has got a lot of content
and you want to view any control which
is at the bottom of the page so you
basically want to scroll down or up or
you can also scroll horizontally using
the horizontal and also vertically using
the vertical axis so tosa provides you
with automation module which is called
the tbox scroll window operation and it
is part of the standard subset so let's
see how we can use that okay so for this
purpose I have created a test case here
and then I'm going to search and ADD
test step here I'm going to search for
the tbox scroll okay and then I'm going
to add this particular module into the
test case now going through the
different module attributes or the
parameters so the first module attribute
is called caption now this is uh the
caption of the application window uh
which you want to scroll uh and caption
would mean that uh it is probably the
title of the page or the window okay
then there is window index so you want
to specify uh which window you want to
scroll based on the opening order so if
the are multiple Pages which have the
same caption you can Define the window
index using which uh tosa can then
perform the operation on that particular
window then uh there is vertical and
horizontal so you have to specify uh
what amount of pixels or lines you want
uh tosa to scroll uh along the pach so
it could be in terms of a vertical axis
or in terms of horizontal axis in both
cases either you have to specify it in
pixels or the
lines then there is something called uh
the mouse policy and there are two
options none or Center so this is
basically tosa will position uh the
mouse pointer uh during the scrolling so
either it could be Center or it would
not move the mouse pointer at all then
there is the direction policy uh there
are three options no Direction policy
vertical uh first and horizontal first
so it basically decides uh what tosa
should scroll along either the vertical
or horizontal axis first okay so if you
mention the vertical first then it will
scroll the vertically and if you mention
horizontal first then it will scroll
horizontally first okay and then there
is also a delay you can mention the time
in milliseconds uh this is basically
when you have both horizontal and
vertical defined then uh there will be a
a delay between these two operations so
tosa will wait for that amount of time
before it does the other operation which
could be horizontal or vertical
scrolling okay so these are all the
different module attributes uh which you
need to Define not all of them are
mandatory uh you need to define the
caption uh if you require you can Define
the index uh you have to Define either
vertical or horizontal so how much you
want to
scroll and then uh the mouse policy can
be left as Center and the direction
policy you can choose between vertical
and horizontal so for this particular
example I have picked up this demo
website uh where uh the infinite scroll
has been implemented so as long as you
are just scrolling it will keep on
increasing
okay so here we are going to scroll
vertically okay uh it is currently at
the top of the page but I want to scroll
vertically downwards okay
so uh let's implement this now um as you
can see uh the title of this page is the
internet right and that would be your
caption right so uh I will mention the
caption here as the internet and then I
will put a regular expression as well so
that if in future this particular title
changes it will still work out okay uh I
don't need to mention any window index
because there's just one window uh and
then I want to do a vertical scroll so
I'm going to mention 500 pixel okay and
that will vertically scroll the page to
pixel Mouse policy I will leave it at as
Center and then Direction policy I will
do vertical first although it's not
required because we are not uh doing a
horizontal scroll right and then we
don't need any delay because uh we are
just doing one scroll not both the
Scrolls
so let's go ahead and execute this test
case and let's see if uh TSA is able to
scroll the page vertically so let's run
it in
scratchbook and now you will see that uh
tosa was able to scroll vertically okay
now we are at the middle or at least
somewhere down the page right if you
want to scroll more then just increase
the pixels okay and um in the results
window also you will see that the test
case has passed
right so that's how you can uh
vertically or horizontally scroll uh
down the page it could be applied to
either a application or even a Windows
based application right so it basically
needs to be a window which has got the
scroll bars like horizontal or vertical
and then you can scroll up or down using
this uh tbox automation module which is
known as tbox scroll window
operation also do keep it in mind that
uh this particular module is not
available in older versions of tosa I'm
currently using the tosa 16 version and
it's available in this particular
version that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next
video